gpsvisualizer.com 2019-10-24

# GPS Visualizer: Privacy Policy

| 

It is GPS Visualizer's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating this Web site. We have adopted this privacy policy to explain what information may be collected on this Web site, how we use this information, and under what circumstances we may disclose the information to third parties. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through the Web site and does not apply to collection of information from other sources. This Privacy Policy sets forth the general rules and policies governing your use of this Web site, and it applies to gpsvisualizer.com and all associated subdomains (e.g. maps.gpsvisualizer.com).

### Web Site Visitors & Statistics

Like most Web servers, GPS Visualizer's server software logs non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each request. GPS Visualizer's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how visitors use the site, as well as provide technical support in the event of a problem. From time to time, GPS Visualizer may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its Web site.

IP addresses, which are _potentially_ personally-identifying information, are also collected as part of the server logs, but are never published individually nor in aggregate.

### Personal Information

GPS Visualizer does not require its users to provide any personal information. However, it is possible that some uploaded data files may contain personally-identifying GPS locations, timestamps, addresses, or other sensitive information. See "Uploaded Data," below.

### Uploaded Data

Many features of GPS Visualizer require visitors to upload a data file, usually a GPS track or spreadsheet. These files are used _only_ to produce maps, profiles, or other geographic output (e.g., GPX or KML files). Users' files are stored on the server for seven days — in case technical support is needed — and then deleted permanently; while on the server, the files are kept in a directory which is not accessible via the World Wide Web. Only the webmaster has access to the uploaded files.

### Security

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, nor any method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Cookies

To enrich and simplify your online experience, GPS Visualizer makes limited use of "cookies." A cookie is a string of information that a Web site stores in a visitor's Web browser, and that the browser provides to the Web site each time the visitor returns. GPS Visualizer uses cookies to store visitor's preferences, and to help GPS Visualizer identify and track repeat visitors. GPS Visualizer visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using GPS Visualizer, with the drawback that certain features of GPS Visualizer's Web sites may be more difficult or not function properly without the aid of cookies. By continuing to navigate this Web site without changing your cookie settings, you hereby acknowledge and agree to GPS Visualizer's use of cookies.

### Advertisements

Ads appearing on this Web site may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set their own cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement, to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies on gpsvisualizer.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers or other third-party partners.

### Links To External Sites

Some content on GPS Visualizer's Web site may contain links to external sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit. We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites, products or services.

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google, Inc. Google Analytics employs cookies that are stored to your computer in order to facilitate an analysis of your use of the site. The information generated by these cookies, such as time, place and frequency of your visits to our site, including your IP address, is transmitted to Google's location in the US and stored there. Google may transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law or where such third parties process this data on Google's behalf. Google states that it will in never associate your IP address with other data held by Google. You can prevent cookies from being installed by adjusting the settings on your browser software accordingly as noted elsewhere in this Privacy Policy. Google Analytics also offers a [deactivation add-on for most current browsers](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) that provides you with more control over what data Google can collect on websites you access. The add-on tells the JavaScript used by Google Analytics not to transmit any information about website visits to Google Analytics. However, the browser deactivation add-on offered by Google Analytics does not prevent information from being transmitted to us or to other web analysis services we may engage.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, GPS Visualizer may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and at GPS Visualizer's sole discretion. GPS Visualizer encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, use the contact information at the bottom of this page.

Return to the GPS Visualizer home page
